

□+1 (203) 940-1857 | ☑ peter@peterk.co | ☑ kazazes | ঐ peter-kazazes | Ⅲ kazazes | У @pkpolls

Summary

Peter is an accomplished and proven political analyst, full stack developer, public speaker, and strategist. While he has worked across industries, his work seems to always come back to where it started - the intersection of politics and technology. Contract consulting in his early teens snowballed into the first social-media-sourced polling platform, Twelect, a massively popular public opinion monitoring tool during the 2012 presidential election. On the basis of Twelect's algorithmic technology, he created Sibyl Vision, a predict-anything public opinion analysis firm. He regularly spoke on Sibyl's research at universities and on national television.

As an engineer, his specialty is developing full-stack, real-time data abstraction platforms for a variety of industries, intent on exposing actionable business intelligence and consumer insight. He is passionate and professionally literate with regards to information security and related evolving

Work Experience

Kennedy for Illinois Chicago, IL

DIGITAL DIRECTOR Nov. 2017 - Apr. 2018

- Designed and executed digital strategy and communications for a statewide gubernatorial campaign
- Conceptualized and built voter ID tools to effectively reach over 100k voters, contingent on SMS identification
- · Served as primary opposition researcher, consequently uncovering multiple routes of corruption in Illinois
- Recruited and facilitated work with outside pollsters
- Organized, directed and shot celebrity and stakeholder endorsements
- Created, implemented, and ran statewide advertising initiatives

Sibyl Vision New York, NY

CTO

2012 - 2017

- Architected, implemented, and ran a quantitative public opinion monitoring platform and brand consultancy
- Used global internet conversation and demographic data married with language-agnostic NLP algorithms to predict consumer behavior
- Built and maintained data-processing infrastructure capable of constantly analyzing a significant percentage of global social conversation, predicting implications of news worthy events in real time
- Developed data analysis frontends for clients intent on maximizing impactful insight into ever-shifting political opinion, ad-spend ROI, and financial instrument pricing
- Managed sales and relationships with media companies, big brands, and celebrities including HBO, Fox News, Beyoncé, and Mondelez International
- · Bootstrapped and managed Sibyl Vision's finances from conception to a seven-figure valuation and twelve-person team

Journal of Law & Cyber Warfare

TECHNOLOGY EDITOR

New York, NY

Jan. 2017 - Jun. 2018

• Process submitted research and editorials, fact check and edit works

- Represent the Journal at security and cyberlaw conferences
- · Manage Journal's physical distribution to high-profile subscribers, including intelligence and defense agencies, CISOs, and judicial officials
- Assist in management of the Journal's annual symposium, speaker booking, and attendance

Assistant to Special Master

New York, NY

FEDERAL DISTRICT COURT, SOUTHERN DISTRICT OF NEW YORK

Jan. 2017 - Mar. 2017

- Assisted the court-appointed special master in a high-profile code plagiarism lawsuit
- · Performed forensic analysis of machine images, source code, repositories, databases, production environments, and developer communications
- Resolved complex disputes between the parties surrounding modifications of a shared codebase
- · Prepared briefs for the special master and the Court regarding the outcome of analysis

Fox Business New York, NY

COMMENTATOR, VARNEY & CO.

Jun. 2012 - Jun. 2013

- Appeared weekly on prime time morning coverage to present and discuss fluctuations in Sibyl Vision's opinion monitoring in light of the day's news
- Featured on specials including Election Night 2012 to demonstrate Sibyl Vision's live modeling of public opinion, exit poll, and demographic data, in conjunction with our continually evolving election outcome predictions

Presentations

Cardozo Law School, Yeshiva University

New York, NY

Data Governance and The Law Feb. 2016

 Lectured to a data governance class on the bulk accessibility of social media postings and the consequences of commercial exploitation of user data

NYU Stern School of Business

New York, NY

DIGITAL MARKETING AND SOCIAL MEDIA STRATEGY

Oct. 2014

• Presented a series of Sibyl Vision's branding-related case studies to graduate school digital marketing class showcasing macro social media analysis and its already-potent impact on marketing related decision making

Aaronson Department of Marketing & International Business, Baruch College

New York, NY

MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS STRATEGY

Mar. 2013

• Discussed the usage of applied sentiment analysis techniques to inform marketing decisions, with a focus on messaging and demographic targeting

Education

University of California, Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

B.A., COMPUTER SCIENCE & LINGUISTICS

On Hold, In Progress